University Development - Record Group 20 WLU.RG.0020
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
University Development - Record Group 20
Date Not Yet Determined
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Washington and Lee University. Development
WLU.RG.0020
x Linear Feet
Scope and Contents
This record group contains materials created by the University Development office during the course of its regular business, including records about its management.
- Corporate & Foundation News, 1999-
- Founders' Day press release, 1979-02-21
- Benefactors: The report of gifts for Washington and Lee University, 1990-1991
- Progress report of college and university campaigns $10,000,000 and over, 1980-02
- Pool Income Fund, Undated
- "The Campus" packet, 1969
  Scope and Contents
  This packet contains information about the campus and prints of photographs.
- "Non In Cautus Futuri: A Guide to Participationin the Future of W&L", Undated
- Parents' Newsletter, 1986-10
- Capital Gifts booklet, circa 1920
  Booklet contains a brochure and pledge card.
- Sample packet of publications, Undated; 9 Item
  List of Development Office publications and several of those publications.
- Development Program Report, 1981-12
- Development Program Second Phase Report, 1979-10-30
- "Not Unmindful of the Future": Making a gift to Washington and Lee, 1991-01
- Estate Planning Program packet, Undated; 1 Item
- Annual Fund Donor sticker, 1985-1986; 1 Item
- Benefactors booklet and campus photographs at completion of Phase 1 of development program, 1920s
- On the Shoulder of Giants: The Campaign for Washington and Lee University, 1992
- Report of Gifts for 1985-1986, 1 Item
- Honored benefactors, 1982
  This file contains the preliminary and final versions
- The Vision of Greatness, 1958-10; 2 Item
- Guest list: Washington and Lee Development Celebration, 1982-05-21-1982-05-22
- An announcement for the Faculty and Staff of Washington and Lee University, 1982-01-19
- Robert E. Lee Associates miscellaneous, 3 Item
  Certificate, 1968.
  Brochure and program for the Eleventh Annual Banquet, Oct. 27, 1978, New York City. Program includes remarks deliverd by W&L President Huntley, "In Defense of Liberal Arts Education."
  Glickstein, Joseph Morris; Huntley, Robert E. R. (Robert Edward Royall)
- Memorandum No.1: The University's Development Program, 1953-10-05; 1 Item
- Celebration of the Development Program Packet, 1982; 2 Item
- The Washington Society Papers
- A campaign for the rising generation at Washington and Lee University, 2001; Elrod, John W.; Boetsch, Howard Laurent; Surface, Frank; 2 Item
  This fundraising DVD includes two centerpiece videos and nine short film segments.
  Washington and Lee University
- Honor Our Past, Build Our Future, The Campaign for Washington and Lee, 2014; Washington and Lee University. Development; 1 Item
- On The Shoulders of Giants, News of the Campaign for Washington and Lee., 1992-03-1995-04; Washington and Lee University. Development; 10 Item
- On the Shoulder of Giants, The Campaign for Washington and Lee., 1990-1995; Washington and Lee University. Development
  General
  This book acknowledges the more than 15,000 alumni, parents, friends of the University who made the Campaign for Washington and Lee a resounding success. We are deeply grateful.
- On the Shoulder of Giants, The Campaign for Washington and Lee. Includes brochures, stationery, and miscellaneous handouts., Washington and Lee University. Development; 10 Item
  Includes a generic letter from William J. Watt, Chairman of the Faculty and Staff Committe, January 20, 1992.
  Washington and Lee University. School of Law
- Non incautus futuri, 2017-09-2018-04
  Spring 2018 issue - The Professor Sidney M. B. Coulling '46 Scholarship Endowment; Ed Spencer '53 Still a Cornerstone of the University; Harry Pememberton, Prof. of Philosophy Emeritus, 1925-2017.
  Washington and Lee University. Development; Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III; Spencer, Edgar Winston; Pemberton, Harrison Joseph
- A Texas-Sized Donation for Virginia Colleges, by Gregory Turley, W&L Class of 1987
  Northen, Mary Moody; Washington and Lee University. James G. Leyburn Library
- Echoes of the Past, Voices of the Future: Honor Our Past, Build Our Future, The Campaign for Washington and Lee, DVD., Washington and Lee University. Campaigns
- The Bridge: News About People Who Are Honoring W&L's Past and Building Its Future., Winter; Washington and Lee University. Development
- Development Office papers on various W&L subjects, 1 Box
  A few of the subjects listed as files of the collection, but most of them are agent links on the record.
  Washington and Lee University. Alpha Beta Tau Chapter. Alpha Phi Omega; Belfield; Brooke, George M.; Brooke, George M., Jr.; Brooke, George M., III; Brooke, George M., IV; Campbell, Henry Donald; Chavis, John; Cheek, Leslie, Jr.; Skylark; Washington and Lee University. Coeducation; Washington and Lee University. Coat of Arms; Confederate States of America. Flags; Washington and Lee University. Fraternities; Washington and Lee University. Gardens; Gilliam, Frank Johnson; Washington and Lee University. Honor System; Washington and Lee University. Ivy; Huntley, Robert E. R. (Robert Edward Royall); Lacy, Beverly Tucker; Lee, Annie Carter; Confederate States of America. Army. Liberty Hall Volunteers; McCormick family; Mulberry Hill; Murray, Charles Fletcher; Peabody, George, 1795-1869; Penick, Mary Monroe; Perry, Frederick John; Washington and Lee University. Reeves Center; Sunnyside Farm; Washington and Lee University. Trees; Vietnam War; Washington and Lee University; Washington and Lee University. W&L Swing; Washington and Lee University. Washington Press; Watt, Alston Parker
  - Notes on the History of Camp Greenbrier, 1898-1998; 1 Files
    Camp Greenbrier is a summer camp for boys nestled in the Allegheny Mountains, on the beautiful Greenbrier River in Alderson, West Virginia. It was founded in 1898 and is the oldest, privately owned summer camp in continuous operation in the United States.
    Camp Greenbrier. Alderson, West Virginia
  - Rockbridge Open Croquet Tournament, 1970-08; Lawrence, Francis McQuaid; McMillan, Lex O., III; 1 Files
    Material concerning the "almost world famous croquet tournament/music festival" that never apparently occurred at A. B. Claytor's farm in Rockbridge County, Virginia.
    Included is a letter from Lex O. McMillan, III, '72, to Francis McQ. Lawrence, '71, thanking him for the donation of the croquet material. Also included in this letter, is information on the W&L Print Shop, where Lex worked the Summer of 1971.
    Croquet; Washington and Lee University. Print Shop
    - History of the Lampost, the Christian residence for students, located at 202 S. Randolph Street, Lexington, Virginia, 1981-1989; 1 Files
      Washington and Lee University. Christians; Washington and Lee University, The Lampost; Carneal, Garry; Calhoun, Samuel W.
  - History of The Lampost, Christian Residence for students, 1981-1989; 1 Files
    The Lampost at 202 S. Randolph Street, Lexington, was born on January 29, 1981. It grew out of the desire and vision of W&L student, Garry Carneal, to secure a house where Christian fellowship could occur and be nutured.
    Prof. Sam Calhoun was on the Board of The Lampost and was the faculty adviser.
    Josh McDowell, affiliated with Campus Crusade for Christ, spoke at W&L on Frebruary 5, 1988.
    Washington and Lee University, The Lampost; Washington and Lee University. Christians; Carneal, Garry; Calhoun, Samuel W.; McDowell, Josh; Lexington Organization for Religious Development
  - Earl N. Levitt Clothing Store, Lexington, Virginia. History, Levitt, Earl N.
    Earl N. Levitt's clothing store on Nelson Street became a Lexington and W&L institution in the mid-20th century.
  - History of Robert E. Lee astride his horse Traveller and young solider on horseback statue in Dallas Texas, 1928-1991; 1 Item
    The bronze equestrian statue was created by noted Canadian sculptor, A. Phimister Proctor, and dedicated on June 12, 1936, in Dallas, Texas. In 1990 a Dallas group worked to restore, preserve it and other statues.
    The original model of the monument was presented to Washington and Lee University for their June 1936 Commencement.
    Lee, Robert E. (Robert Edward), 1807-1870
  - History of the Washington and Lee Polo Club and Ponies, 1974-1975; 1 Files
    Mainly correspondence dealing with gifts of named ponies to the W&L Polo Club.
    Washington and Lee University. Polo Club; Rayborn, G. Wayne
  - Elizabeth Myers Bentley material, 2005-2012; 1 Files
    W&L Department of Music, Theater and Dance, Robert O. and Elizabeth M. Bentley Music Event programs and invitation.
    A Celebration of Life program for Elizabeth, a Mead Assoc. real estate pamphlet for Elizabeth's home, "Longue Vue," on Ross Road Extended, and a photocopy of a photo of the Bentley Musical, Chicago cast with Elizabeth, February 2010.
    Robert O. and Elizabeth Bentley Endowment for the Performing Arts; Bentley, Elizabeth; Washington and Lee University. Department of Music